# Ren

# Estep

renestep.com n.ren.estep@gmail.com

Github: storiesOfRen Codepen: ren\_estep Dev: stories\_of\_ren

## **Summary**

As a software engineer, I come from an alternative background, which focused on fine arts. My experience with art and design gives me an interesting perspective, especially when collaborating on teams and being able to contribute to design discussions on projects. A lot of the growth I've seen in myself has led to a passion for building web apps with accessibility in mind.

# **Experience**

11/2017 - Present: Software Engineer - Mile Two, LLC

- Collaborated on and developed many projects utilizing ReactJS, Next.js, NodeJs, Python, Postgres and MongoDB.
- Introduced improvements to accessibility compliance through integrating Deque's axe-core wrapper on projects and eslint accessibility plugins to catch code that produces inaccessible applications.
- Mentored associate level and intern employees through pairing sessions and public presentations on accessibility and CSS skills.
- Collaborates with design and CSE teams for a more well rounded understanding of projects.

**04/2017 - 11/2017**: Frontend Web Developer & Graphic Designer - MRS Electronic

- Design and produce iconography for mobile and desktop applications.
- Developed multiple projects using Javascript, AngularJS, CSS, Swift, and C#.

**04/2016 - 04/2017**: Manager of Marketing & Creative services - MRS Electronic

- Maintain website content.
- Design, produce, and schedule content for social media.
- Design UI wireframes.

01/2015 - 05/2016: Adjunct Instructor - Edison Community College

 Teaching and observing Introduction to Humanities. Covering art in all its forms while catering to an appreciation for education of creative natures.

## **Certifications**

AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner - issued: 12 / 2020 expires: 12/2023 FreeCodeCamp Front End Web Development Certification - Issued 09/2017

### **Skills**

### **Essential**

**Public Speaking** 

Mentoring

Collaboration

### **LANGUAGES & FRAMEWORKS**

HTML5

CSS3

JavaScript

SASS

ReactJS

NextJS

Node

Python

**Postgres** 

MongoDB

#### **TOOLS**

Visual Studio Code

**Chrome Developer Tools** 

Lighthouse

Axe accessibility tools

## **Education**

2015 - Sinclair Community College - Web Programming Course Work

2012 - Wright State University - Computer Science Course Work

2011 - MFA - University of Tennessee - 4D Media Concentration

2008 - BFA - Wright State University - Photography Concentration